# Yang, Bo

#### Developer

+1-415-420-9693



https://yang-bo.com



pop.atry@gmail.com



pop\_atry



yang\_bo



955091



Atry

## About me —

I am a developer who knows how to create application frameworks.

I founded a number of open-source projects for creating micro-services. neural networks, reactive GUIs, and DSLs, which are stared 3000+ times on GitHub.

My current interests include machine learning infrastructure and the application of functional programming languages to real-world problems.

# Skills

Scala

Machine Learning

Software Design

Agile Project Management

Hack \*5.5 Haxe \*5.5 OpenCL \*5 DevOps \*5 ActionScript \*4 C++ \*4 Java \*4 JavaScript \*4 Rust ★4 OCaml ★4 Testing ★3 C \*3 Spark \*3 Akka \*3

(\*)[The skill scale is from 0 (Fundamental Awareness) to 6 (Expert).]

#### Open-source projects

2021-2022 HHVM C++/Rust/OCaml is Meta's virtual machine running Hack. I ported the open source branch of HHVM to Nix and created CI pipeline for building, testing, and packaging HHVM. since 2018 is a framework to extend Scala language features in libraries. I also ported this framework to Haskell as Control.Dsl. since 2016 DeepLearning.scala and Compute.scala Scala are libraries for creating complex neural networks. since 2015 Binding.scala Scala is a reactive templating language for creating web and desktop GUI. 2015-2016 Microbuilder Haxe / Scala / Java / JavaScript is a toolkit to build system across micro-services implemented in various languages communicating via RESTful JSON API. since 2012 haxe-continuation

Haxe

provides async/await syntax for Haxe.

since 2010 protoc-gen-as3 ActionScript3

is a Protocol Buffers plugin for ActionScript 3. other 100+ of open-source projects

## **Publications**

since 2007

2017 DeepLearning.scala 2.0: Statically Typed Neural Networks 2017 More than React 2009 Adobe Flex 3: Training from the Source translator Talks 2017 Deeplearning. Scala ——Thoughts and practices on open source deep

learning framework DRTC 2017 Monadic Deep Learning Strange Loop 2017 **Neural Networks & Functional Programming** ArchData Summit · Beijing 2016 More than Async QCon · Beijing 2015 Specific-domain extension in an universal language **ECUG Con** 

#### Experience

2019-2022 Meta Platforms Inc Software Developer I built machine learning infrastructure to detect payment fraud and integrated it into a variety of products. Then I joined the Hack/HHVM OSS team, where I was in charge of maintaining HHVM's open-source branch.

2015-2019 Thoughtworks Inc Senior Consultant / Lead Consultant I maintained a number of open-source projects sponsored by ThoughtWorks. I also took the role of Consultant or Tech Lead in various delivery teams for creating mobile and web applications, as well as data platforms.

2014 Shenzhen QiFun Network Corp., LTD I led the Q-Force Team in developing a game engine along with its related tools, and two mobile games.

2011-2013 Shenzhen Putaoteng Network Technology Co., Ltd. Co-founder I led the start-up team in developing a 3D side-scrolling game engine VinyHome and a social game Nan Da Nu Pei.

2008-2011 NetEase. Inc. Chief Programmer

I participated in various product teams as a developer or the technical lead, including Zhan Guo Feng Yun (web game), Ka Pai Dui Jue (web game), Deepcold (3D game

2007 Beijing HiPiHi Information Technology Corp.,Ltd Software Engineer I developed variant components of both client-side and server-side for a 3D virtual world, HiPiHi World,

2006-2007 Beijing AutoNavi Software Co., Ltd. Software Engineer As a developer, I developed some components for a 3D navigation software.

#### Education

2002-2006 Southwest University of Political Science and Law Bachelor Of Laws